silkfred.com 2018-12-31

# SilkFred: Unique Women’s Clothing from 600+ Online Fashion Brands

### May 2018

  * Introduction
  * Information we may collect from you
  * Cookies and other technologies
  * Uses made of your information
  * Information sharing
  * Public forums
  * External links
  * Payment processing
  * Security
  * Storage of your information
  * Your rights
  * Contacting us

## Introduction

This is the privacy and cookies policy for [www.silkfred.com](http://www.silkfred.com/) ( **Site** ). The Site is operated by or on behalf of SilkFred Limited (we, us and our). For the purposes of European and UK data protection law, (the "Data Protection Law"), the data controller is SilkFred Ltd, 25 Woodseer Street, London, E1 5HA.We are committed to protecting your privacy on-line. This policy (together with our Online Terms of Supply and any other documents referred to in it) sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us. Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it.

By using the Site, you acknowledge that you have read and understood the terms of this privacy policy and the use of personal data described.

We reserve the right to change this privacy policy from time to time by changing it on the Site. This privacy policy was last updated on May 2018.

## Information we may collect from you

We may collect and process the following information about you:

**Information you give us**

  * information (such as your name, email address, postal address and telephone number) that you provide by completing forms on the Site, including if you register as a user of the Site, upload or submit any material via the Site, request any information, or enter into any competition or promotion we may operate or sponsor;
  * in connection with an account sign-in facility, your log-in and password details;
  * details of any transactions made by you through the Site with us or Brands; credit and debit card information (where saved by you)
  * communications you send to us, for example to report a problem or to submit queries, concerns or comments regarding the Site or its content; and
  * information from surveys that we may, from time to time, run for research purposes, if you choose to respond to, or participate in, them.

You are under no obligation to provide any such information. However, if you should choose to withhold requested information, we may not be able to provide you with certain services.

**Information we collect about you** With regard to each of your visits to our Site we will automatically collect the following information by means of cookies and/or other similar technologies: 

  * technical information, including the Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet, your login information, browser type and version, time zone setting, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform or mobile device;
  * information about your visit, including the full Uniform Resource Locators (URL), clickstream to, through and from our Site (including date and time), products you viewed or searched for, page response times, download errors, length of visits to certain pages, page interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks, and mouse-overs), methods used to browse away from the page, and any phone number used to call our customer service team.

See Cookies and other technologies for more information. 

## Information we receive from other sources

This is information we receive about you if you use another website we operate or another services we provide. In this case we will have informed you when we collected that data if we intend to share those data internally and combine it with data collected on this Site. We will also have told you for what purpose we will share and combine your data.

We are working closely with third parties (including, for example, business partners, sub-contractors in technical, payment and delivery services, advertising networks, analytics providers, and search information providers).

## Cookies and other technologies

Our Site uses cookies to distinguish you from other users of our website. When you interact with the Site, we try to make that experience simple and meaningful. When you visit the Site, a web server sends a cookie or other similar technology to your computer or mobile device (as the case may be). Cookies are small pieces of information which are issued to your computer or mobile device (as the case may be) when you visit a website and which store and sometimes track information. A number of cookies we use last only for the duration of your web session and expire when you close your browser. Other cookies are used to remember you when you return to the Site and will last for longer.

The cookies and/or other similar technologies we use collect information, such as the type of internet browser or mobile device you use, any website from which you have come to the Site, your IP address and/or the operating system of your computer or mobile device.

We use the following sorts of cookies and/or other similar technologies, such as tracking GIFs, web beacons and pixel codes, either alone or in combination with each other to create a unique device ID: 

  * **Strictly necessary cookies.** These are cookies that are required for the operation of our Site and under our terms with you. They include, for example, cookies that enable you to log into secure areas of our Site, use a shopping cart or make use of e-billing services.
  * **Analytical/performance cookies.** They allow us to recognise and count the number of visitors and to see how visitors move around our Site when they are using it. This helps us for our legitimate purposes to improve the way our Site works, for example, by ensuring that users are finding what they are looking for easily.
  * **Functionality cookies.** These are used to recognise you when you return to our Site. This enables us, subject to your choices and preferences, to personalise our content for you, greet you by name and remember your preferences (for example, your choice of language or region).
  * **Targeting cookies.** These cookies gather information about the pages on the Site that you visit, and also other information about other websites that you visit, so as to place you in a "market segment". This information is collected by reference to the IP address that you are using and/or your unique user ID, and includes information about the county and city you are in, together with the name of your internet service provider. This information is then used to place interest-based advertisements on the Site which it is believed will be relevant to your market segment. For more information about this type of interest based advertising, and about how to turn this feature off please visit [http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/.](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/)

Some of the cookies used by the Site are set by us, and some are set by third parties who are delivering services on our behalf.

#### Our cookies

You can find more information about the individual cookies we use and the purposes for which we use them in the tables below: 

##### SilkFred Cookies

Cookie | Name | Purpose  
---|---|---  
Silkfred Cookies | first_visit_triggered | Used to manage pop-ups  
| cookie_notice_dismissed | Ensures that the cookie notice des not reappear once our cookie notice has been dismissed  
| skip_holding | Enables users to skip a registration page  
| selected_products_sizes | is being used for: <https://www.silkfred.com/outlet> to know which sizes the user has selected to view outlet products to prevent the need to reselect when the page is refreshed.  
  
##### Third Party Cookies

Cookie | Name | Purpose | More information  
---|---|---|---  
Facebook Cookies |  | Ad conversion tracking | <https://www.facebook.com/policies/cookies/>  
Klaviyo Cookie - TG | __kla_id__kla_viewed | This cookie enables us to track the products you engage with and purchase in order to provide marketing emails that are targeted at your individual interests | <https://help.klaviyo.com/hc/en-us/articles/115005076767-Klaviyo-Web-Tracking>  
MailChimp - TG |  | MailChimp uses session cookies to help our website remember changes made as our users move from page to page. With secure sites like MailChimp, session cookies work to keep the user logged in so they aren't required to enter their credentials whenever they navigate to a new page. These cookies are deleted after the session ends. | <https://kb.mailchimp.com/accounts/account-setup/how-mailchimp-uses-cookies>  
Google Analytics - AP | ga | Lives for 2 years - Used to distinguish users | <https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/analyticsjs/cookie-usage>  
_gid | Lives for 24h - Used to distinguish users  
_gat | Lives for 1 min - Used to throttle request rate.  
AMP_TOKEN | Lives for 30 sec to 1 year - Contains a token that can be used to retrieve a Client ID from AMP Client ID service.   
_gac_<property-id> | Lives for 30 sec to 1 year - Contains a token that can be used to retrieve a Client ID from AMP Client ID service.  
__utma | Lives for 90 days - Contains campaign related information for the user. If you have linked your Google Analytics and AdWords accounts, AdWords website conversion tags will read this cookie unless you opt-out.  
2 years from set/update. Used to distinguish users and sessions. The cookie is created when the javascript library executes and no existing __utma cookies exists. The cookie is updated every time data is sent to Google Analytics.  
__utmt | 10 minutes. Used to throttle request rate.  
__utmb | 30 mins from set/update. Used to determine new sessions/visits. The cookie is created when the javascript library executes and no existing __utmb cookies exists. The cookie is updated every time data is sent to Google Analytics.  
__utmz | 6 months from set/update. Stores the traffic source or campaign that explains how the user reached your site. The cookie is created when the javascript library executes and is updated every time data is sent to Google Analytics.  
__utmc | End of browser session. Not used in ga.js. Set for interoperability with urchin.js. Historically, this cookie operated in conjunction with the __utmb cookie to determine whether the user was in a new session/visit.  
GoSquared - AP | gs_u_{SITE_TOKEN} | User identifier cookie, which stores a unique user id, page/visit counts, and last visit time | <https://www.gosquared.com/legal/privacy/statement/>  
gs_p_{SITE_TOKEN} | Used to keep track of user within a browsing session  
gs_v_GSN-808091-L |   
gs_t_GSN-808091-L |   
gs_u_GSN-808091-L |   
Attraqt Product View - FN | LMDATA | Not using an actual cookie, but local storage. However information is being sent back to the server, so this operates in a similar way to a cookie.  
Local storage has no expiry date  
Data: user return yes/no, date of last & current visit, visit count, product. | N/A  
LMSITEREFERRER  
LMSID  
LMUID  
Privy - TG | privy_signedup_354929 | Cookie enablers for Email Pop Ups | <https://privy.com/features>  
_privy_B0E315D5ED6DAAC334F02229  
_privy_match_session  
_privy_a  
_privy_b  
ShareThis - TG | __unam | The "__unam" cookie is set as part of the ShareThis service and monitors "click-stream" activity, e.g. web pages viewed, navigation from page to page, time spent on each page etc. The Share. This service only personally identifies you if you have separately signed up with ShareThis for a ShareThis account and given them your consent. | <http://www.sharethis.com/privacy/>  
__sharethis_cook | The browser cookie tracks the content viewed by the visitor and pages of websites which use ShareThis Publisher Applications. This might be a legacy cookie unless we still use the sharethis buttons on the blog? Not on the site anymore  
Microsoft Bing Adds - FN | _uetsid | 30 minutes. This is a cookie utilised by Microsoft Bing Ads and is a tracking cookie. It allows us to engage with a user that has previously visited our website. |   
Stripe - SN | __stripe_mid | Session cookies - Provides a unique session identifier for dashboard Users | <https://stripe.com/cookies-policy/legal>  
__stripe_sid:  
ZopIM (Zendesk) - SN | __zlcmid | These cookies are managed by ZopIM, who provide the technology behind our 'live chat' system. The __zlcmid cookie allows you to continue a chat with us as you view different pages on our site, or if you come back to the site later. If you choose to disable this service from the live chat window's options menu or the 'ON'/'OFF' switch above | <https://www.zendesk.com/company/customers-partners/#cookie-policy>  
__zlcstore  
ZD-buid  
ZD-suid  
Feathr - TG | f_id | 1 year. Tracks individual page visits to distinguish between users. | <https://help.feathr.co/getting-started/privacy/information-to-add-to-your-privacy-policy>  
Hotjar | _hjIncludedInSample | This session cookie is set to let Hotjar know whether that visitor is included in the sample which is used to generate Heatmaps, Funnels, Recordings, etc. | <https://help.hotjar.com/hc/en-us/articles/115011789248-Hotjar-Cookies>  
| cto_lwid | HTTP cookie. These cookies are used to support your experience on the site and include user-selected options, site navigation aids, etc. Generally, no personally identifiable data is collected with these types of cookies. |   
  
Except for SilkFred essential cookies, all cookies used on our Site will expire after two years.

#### Disabling cookies

Most web and mobile device browsers automatically accept cookies but, if you prefer, you can change your browser to prevent that or to notify you each time a cookie is set. You can also learn more about cookies by visiting [www.allaboutcookies.org](https://www.allaboutcookies.org/) which includes additional useful information on cookies and how to block cookies using different types of browser or mobile device. Please note, however, that by blocking or deleting cookies used on the Site, you may not be able to take full advantage of the Site.

The effect of disabling cookies depends on which cookies you disable, but in general the Site may not operate properly if cookies are switched off. If you only disable third party cookies, you will not be prevented from making purchases on our Site. If you disable all cookies, you will be unable to complete a purchase on our Site.

If you want to disable cookies you need to change your website browser settings to reject cookies. How you can do this will depend on the browser you use. Further details on how to disable cookies for the most popular browsers are set out below:

##### For Microsoft Internet Explorer:

  1. Choose the menu "tools" then "Internet Options"
  2. Click on the "privacy" tab
  3. Select the setting the appropriate setting

##### For Google Chrome

  1. Choose Settings> Advanced
  2. Under "Privacy and security," click "Content settings".
  3. Click "Cookies"

##### For Safari

  1. Choose Preferences > Privacy
  2. Click on "Remove all Website Data"

##### For Mozilla firefox

  1. Choose the menu "tools" then "Options"
  2. Click on the icon "privacy"
  3. Find the menu “cookie” and select the relevant options

##### For Opera 6.0 and further

  1. Choose the menu "Files" > "Preferences"
  2. Privacy

Where you have not set your permissions, we may also separately prompt you regarding our use of cookies on the Site. 

## Uses made of your information

We use information held about you in the following ways: 

  * **Information you give to us.** We will use this information: 
    * to carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us and to provide you with the information, products and services that you request from us;
    * verify and carry out financial transactions in relation to payments you make online;
    * to provide you, with information about goods or services we feel may interest you, if you have _consented_ on the form on which we collect your data (the order form **OR** registration form to create an account with the site) to receiving marketing material from us. This may include information about and or third parties about which you have expressly indicated an interest (including categories of Brands) and consented to receive marketing material, when asked by us;
    * to notify you about changes to our service or policies;
    * to ensure in our legitimate interests that content from our Site is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer.
  * **Information we collect about you.** We will use this information: 
    * to administer our Site under our terms and for internal operations, including troubleshooting, and, in our legitimate interests, data analysis, testing, research, statistical and survey purposes;
    * to improve our Site to ensure that content is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer;
    * to allow you to participate in interactive features of our service, when you choose to do so;
    * as part of our legitimate efforts to keep our Site safe and secure;
    * for our legitimate interest of measuring or understanding the effectiveness of advertising we serve to you and others, and to deliver relevant advertising to you;
    * to make suggestions and recommendations to you and other users of our Site about goods or services that may interest you or them, subject to your stated preferences where relevant.
  * **Information we receive from other sources.** We will combine this information with information you give to us and information we collect about you. We will use this information and the combined information for the purposes set out above (depending on the types of information we receive).

#### Marketing Choices

You can tell us not to contact you with information regarding our products and services or those of Brands or third parties, either at the point such information is collected on the Site or, where you do not wish us to continue to use your information in this way, by following the unsubscribe instructions on any communications sent to you. You can also exercise the right at any time by contacting us (using the Contacting us details at the end of this privacy policy) or by changing your marketing communications preferences in our customer preference centre at any time.

## Information sharing

You agree that we have the right to share your personal information with:

  * Any member of our group, which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries.
  * The following third parties including: 
    * business partners, sub-contractors, and suppliers, including Brands that you make purchases from on the Site for the performance of any contract we enter into with you;
    * advertising agencies and advertising networks that require the data to select and serve relevant adverts to you and others on our behalf.
    * analytics and search engine providers that assist us in the improvement and optimisation of our Site and subject to the cookie section of this policy.

We may also share your personal data under the following circumstances:

  * In the event that we sell any part of our business or assets, in which case we will disclose your personal data to the prospective buyer of such business or assets subject to the terms of this privacy policy.
  * If we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our terms of supply terms and other agreements with you; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of SilkFred, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection, credit risk reduction and law enforcement purposes.

## Public forums

The Site may, from time to time, make chat rooms, message boards, news groups and/or other public forums available to its users. Any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when using these and never disclose your personal information.

## External links

The Site may, from time to time, contain links to external sites. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites. We are not responsible for the privacy policies or the content of such sites.

## Payment processing

Payments made on the Site are made through our payment gateway providers, Stripe and/or PayPal. You will be providing credit or debit card information directly to Stripe and/or PayPal which operates a secure server to process payment details, encrypting your credit/debit card information and authorising payment. Information which you supply to Stripe and/or PayPal is not within our control and is subject to Stripe's and/or PayPal's own privacy policy and terms and conditions.

## Security

We place great importance on the security of all personal information associated with our users. We have security measures in place to attempt to protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of personal information under our control. For example, our security and privacy policies are periodically reviewed and enhanced as necessary and only authorised personnel have access to personal information. Whilst we cannot ensure or guarantee that loss, misuse or alteration of information will never occur, we use all reasonable efforts to prevent it.

You should bear in mind that submission of information over the internet is never entirely secure. We cannot guarantee the security of information you submit via the Site whilst it is in transit over the internet and any such submission is at your own risk.

It is advisable to close your browser when you have finished your user session to help ensure others do not access your personal information if you use a shared computer or a computer in a public place.

## Storage of your information

Your personal information which we collect is sent to and stored on secure servers located in the UK. Such storage is necessary in order to process the information. Personal information submitted may be transferred by us to our other offices and/or to the third parties mentioned in the circumstances described above (see Information sharing), which may be situated outside the European Economic Area (EEA) and may be processed by staff operating outside the EEA. Where we transfer your personal information we will take all reasonable steps to ensure that your privacy rights continue to be protected.

Where personal data is transferred in relation to providing our services we will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy and it subject to appropriate safeguards, such as relying on a recognised legal adequacy mechanism which may include by entering into EC approved standard contractual clauses relevant to transfers of personal information (see <http://ec.europa.eu/justice/dataprotection/internationaltransfers/transfer/index_en.html>)

## Your rights

You have the right under certain circumstances:

  * to be provided with a copy of your personal data held by us;
  * to request the rectification or erasure of your personal data held by us;
  * to request that we cease processing your data;
  * to request that we restrict the processing of your personal data (while we verify or investigate your concerns with this information, for example);
  * to request that your data be transferred to a third party.

We will inform you (before collecting your data) if we intend to use your data for marketing purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes. You can also object to receiving further marketing at any time without detriment.

You can also exercise the rights listed above at any time by contacting us at [privacy@silkfred.com](mailto:privacy@silkfred.com).

Please contact us at [privacy@silkfred.com](mailto:privacy@silkfred.com) with any questions you have about this policy or data protection at SilkFred. You can submit any questions you have about an order you have placed, ordering in general, or any complaint or concern in relation to any product ordered by email to [hello@silkfred.com](mailto:hello@silkfred.com)
